<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Engineering on scarbrough-trx@GitHub</title>
    <link>/tags/software-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Engineering on scarbrough-trx@GitHub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>.NET Core - xUnit Tests with Repository Pattern and IUNitOfWork</title>
      <link>/post/dotnet-core-xunit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dotnet-core-xunit/</guid>
      <description>After some hours of frustration and asking myself whether I should have used Unit of Work in the first place (there are already layers of abstraction in the standard .NET Core template project) I managed to get a functioning xUnit test method that mocks the repositories, populates them with data and verifies the model returned by a controller method.
Setting Up a Unit Test Project Add a xUnit project to the solution, then add an assembly reference in that to the project being tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Core 6 - Dependency Injection, Repository Pattern and Unit of Work</title>
      <link>/post/repository-pattern-and-uow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/repository-pattern-and-uow/</guid>
      <description>A repository pattern exists to add another layer of abstraction between the application logic and the data layer, using dependency injection to decouple the two. It&amp;rsquo;s not my preferred way of doing things, because of the effort and complexity involved, and I&amp;rsquo;m certainly not the only person who initially struggled to understand the concepts behind it. Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s apparent that Entity Framework makes heavy use of that dependency injection already. But a Repository Pattern is widely considered - by software engineers far more experienced than I am - best practice for engineering services that deal with critical data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
