<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on scarbrough-trx@GitHub</title>
    <link>/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on scarbrough-trx@GitHub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/docs/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/about/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Michael, and my professional background is in .NET software engineering (C#, MVC, MSSQL, etc), though this is within the context of an ecosystem of other technologies related to deployment, version control, distribution and testing. Aside from that, I do have some expertise with the Linux operating system (mostly variants of Debian and openSUSE), which I have been using since ~2005.
After several years working for the public sector, where I provided technical support for secure communications networks, I decided to take this in a more academic direction, studying computer security at the University of South Wales, and managing to earn a Masters&amp;rsquo; degree in 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Projects</title>
      <link>/docs/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>Multi-Function Terminal Essentially this is a custom Web browser application based on the latest .NET Framework and WebView2, but it is configurable by the persons administrating the terminal and is designed to run on remotely-managed client machines.
Technical Debt and Legacy Software Essentially making sure that software is more secure, robust, maintainable and documented.
Wake On LAN Portal This is a Web portal that enables members of an organisation to wake on-premise computers, so they become accessible over Remote Desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repositories</title>
      <link>/docs/repositories/repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/repositories/repositories/</guid>
      <description>Code Samples Miscellaneous code samples and templates are stored here.
Go&amp;hellip;
INFOSEC Computer and network security code and scripts.
Go&amp;hellip;
PHAROS Project templates, mainly .NET Core.
Go&amp;hellip;
Python A collection of old Python scripts and projects.
Go&amp;hellip;
Systems Integration APIs, Web Services, etc. Most the code here is for the older versions of .NET Framework.
Dataset Lookup Service API Generic Service Bus Consumer Go&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Toolkit</title>
      <link>/docs/toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/toolkit/</guid>
      <description>Azure Storage Explorer
Docker Desktop
GitHub Desktop
LINQPad
MkDocs (Material)
Postman
Windows Terminal
Wireshark
Editors and Development Environments emacs org mode
Notepad++
Visual Studio
Visual Studio Code
SQL and Databases Azure Data Studio
Entity Framework Core Tools
MySQL Server
MySQL Workbench
SQL Server Management Studio</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links</title>
      <link>/docs/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/resources/</guid>
      <description>Codemanship Blog Codemanship&amp;rsquo;s Blog
Babel This is a JavaScript compiler and translator. Could be useful for generating backwards-compatible code.
Babel JavaScript Compiler
GitHub Commands Cheat Sheet All the commonly-used GitHub commands.
GitHub Commands Cheat Sheet
Hacker News Technology-related news items and blog posts that might be of interest.
Hacker News
Netlify Integrate Web site hosting with DevOps and GitHub. Also provides ready-made static site generator templates.
Netlify
OWASP Top Ten Open Web Application Security Project&amp;rsquo;s list of top application vulnerabilities and recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
